There is a plan that she'll use in project management often may be created by the business analyst or
contributed to your project by the Business Analyst and that's the project benefits management plan
the benefits management plan is it's a plan that describes how well you create benefits for the organization.
How is this going to be who of the organization.
How will it create value.
So we have this idea of benefits for the organization benefits realization for the organization.
How will you maximize project benefits and then how will the organization sustain these benefits.
So it benefits management plan describes benefits for the organization.
But what is a benefit will benefit benefit is something that your project creates that will give value
to the organization and the project beneficiaries the end user or the customer or the public at large.
So a benefit is something that's good you want benefits.
So how do you create benefits how you maximize benefits and how will you sustain the benefits.
The project benefits management plan has a lot of characteristics we should be familiar with for your
PMI exam.
First off what are the target benefits so what are the tangible and intangible benefits.
Describe business value in tangible and intangible terms here for the target benefits then the street
Jick strategic alignment how with how will the project align to the business strategies.
Do we have a time frame.
So when will benefits be realized.
So by phases is there a short term or long term.
Is it an ongoing.
So once this is created it's going to have ongoing benefits for the organization.
So when will we have benefits realization.
So those are three characteristics of the plant.
Three more.
What are the metrics how will you measure to show us benefits have been realized.
So before and after.
So this was the speed of our network before the project and this is the speed after.
So what are the benefits realize So how will you show us this.
So we want to see some results before and after more profits increase so the number of defects have
gone down or helped us.
Calls have been diminished.
So how do you measure this and that helps see our A-Y which is a benefit.
What assumptions do you have in place.
Remember an assumption something to you that you believe to be true but you've not proven it to be true.
So what assumptions do you have in your project about these benefits or what do you think has to exist
or will remain in place in order for benefits to come into fruition.
And then what risk may be in your project that could threaten the benefits.
So you know the network example may be well more traffic more users because now we have more bandwidth
we're downloading you know bigger things or using utilizing that so it catches up or we have a new piece
of software that's great we can work faster but it's more complex so there's a learning curve.
So what risk are maybe the opposite side of the benefits.
All right good job.
That's the end of this lecture.
Keep moving forward.